(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
さあ　日々と　昼夜逆転　ボク成三十ワット
Now, day by day, day and night reversed, I'm a 30-watt success.
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンド仲間にヤッホー
A subculture boy with a Telecaster on his back says 'yoo-hoo' to his bandmates.
アルバイトはネクラモード
Part-time job is in gloomy mode.
対バンにはエイティーンフィルター
Eighteen filters for the battle of the bands.
独り自尊心で逃げるギガボーイ
A Giga boy running away with his lonely pride.
ゆとり坊ちゃん　お嬢ちゃん　おカネも才能も
Yutori boys and young ladies, having money and talent...
なまじっかあるだけ厄介でやんす
...is just a hassle when you only have a bit of it.
Boys be ambitious...
like girls be amedious
長い前髪　君誰の信者
With your long bangs, whose believer are you?
信者
Believer
勘違いすんな　教祖はお前だ
Don't get it wrong, you're the cult leader.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll.
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
The electric guitar you're strumming...
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ君のすべてを
Come on, take all of yourself...
曝け出してみせろよ
...and show it off!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll.
さあ　御法　いい曲書いてる？
Now, at the peak, are you writing good songs?
動員増えてる？
Is your audience growing?
知名度あるけど人気はそんなにないから色々大変ですね
You have the name recognition but not the popularity, so it's quite tough, isn't it?
はっきり言うなよ匿名アイコン
Don't say it so bluntly, anonymous icon.
はっきり見せない実写のアイコン
An icon of a person that doesn't clearly show them.
いい年こいて自意識まだボーイ
At your age, you're still a self-conscious boy.
ぶっちゃけどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
To be honest, no matter how smartly or slyly you do it...
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
...ten years later, the makeup will have come off.
Boys be ambitious...
high-base also-man
生きるためだ　決めろ手枷セルフィー
It's to survive; decide on the handcuffed selfie.
セルフィー
Selfie
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you dare die, for both our sakes.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll.
薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい
Even a shallow love song is fine.
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
目の前のあの子を
That girl right in front of you...
撃ち抜いてみせろよ
...show me you can shoot her through!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki-roki's rock 'n' rock 'n' roll.
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
You can't be satisfied with just stalling.
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコートは
The Throat Coat tea brought to the studio...
安心不安心プレッシャーでいっぱい
...is filled with relief, anxiety, and pressure.
実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません
Actually, I've had a cold since yesterday and lost my voice.
はあ？
Huh?
はあーー...
Haaah...
寝るとは寝ていねー
I'm not sleeping, definitely not.
Baby
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにな!
Don't you die on me, either of us!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rockin' Rock 'n' Roll
かき鳴らせ エレクトリックギターを
Strum that electric guitar
Don't stop! Don't stop!
さあ君のすべてを
Now, everything about you
曝け出してみせろよ
Show it all to me
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki Roki's Rockin' Rock 'n' Roll
ロキロキの
Roki Roki's
ロックンロール
Rock 'n' Roll
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you die
死にたかねえのは
Not wanting to die
お互い様!
Is mutual!
何をしても不器用で
No matter what I do, I'm clumsy
何かとミスしてばっか
And I'm always making mistakes
ダメダメな私だって
Even someone as useless as me
できることがあるの
Has things she can do
凹んで悲しくたって
Even when I'm depressed and sad
笑顔にしてあげるんだ
I'll make you smile
ここにいるから早く
I'm right here, so quickly
私を見つけてね
Find me, okay?
愛してもっと
Love me more
いつでも隣にいるし
I'm always by your side
いつでも一緒に笑える
We can always laugh together
私をたくさん知って
Get to know me more
たくさん好きって言って
Tell me you love me lots
わがままで朝も苦手
I'm selfish and not a morning person
ドジだしダメダメだけど
I'm clumsy and useless, but
それでも私のことを
Even so, please keep
見ててね
Watching over me
描く夢の未来へ続く
Continuing to the future of the dreams I draw
道をキミと歩けますように
I hope I can walk the path with you
ねえもっと ねえもっと
Hey, more, hey, more
好きになってもらいたいの
I want you to fall in love with me
頭の中はキミばっかって
My head is filled only with you
余所見なんて向かせないで
Don't look anywhere else
ああもうヤキモチしちゃうわ
Ah, I'm already getting jealous
Ah Ah
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to love you forever and ever
心の奥もときめいちゃうくらいに
So much that even the depths of my heart throb
こっち向いててよダーリン
Look this way, darling
もう離さないから
Because I'll never let you go
絶対に
Never
愛してもっと
Love me more
キミがいるから私
Because you're here, I
いつでも頑張れるんだ
Can always do my best
落ち込んで悲しくたって
Even when I'm feeling down and sad
キミがいるから
Because you're here
みんな! 今日あくシオ3Dライブに来てくれてありがとう!
Everyone! Thank you for coming to the Akushio 3D Live today!
あくあ色に染まれー!
Dye yourselves in Aqua's color!
キミがいるから歩いてこれた
I was able to walk here because you were there
キミがいなくちゃ前も見れない
Without you, I can't even see ahead
嫌なこととか辛いこととかあっても
Even if bad or painful things happen
キミの力でここまで笑ってこれたんだ
With your strength, I've been able to laugh all the way here
今度はもっと私がグッと引っ張って
Next time, I'll pull you along even harder
連れて行くんだ
And take you with me
キミがいるから私がいるの
I exist because you're here
こんな私を愛してくれる?
Can you love someone like me?
ねえもっと ねえもっと
Hey, more, hey, more
まだもっと 受け止めてよねえ
Even more, accept me, hey
ねえ
Hey
さあ声を上げて
Now, raise your voice
ねえもっと ねえもっと
Hey, more, hey, more
好きになってもらいたいの
I want you to fall in love with me
いつでもそう私ばっか見たいに
I want to be the only one you look at, always
余所見なんて向かせないわ
I won't let you look anywhere else
ほら夢中にさせちゃうわ
Look, I'll make you crazy for me
Ah Ah
ずっとずっと好きがいいの
I want to love you forever and ever
心も体も染まっちゃうくらいに
So much that your heart and body are dyed
こっち向いててよダーリン
Look this way, darling
ふたり もう離さないから
I won't let go of the two of us anymore
絶対に 絶対に 絶対よ
Absolutely, absolutely, I mean it
約束だよ
It's a promise
I love you oh oh oh...
愛しちゃう もっと
I'll love you even more
プライドばっか見てないで
Don't just stare at your pride
パッパッパッラリラ 踊れよ
Pa-pa-pa-rarira, dance along
互い互い様 よそで
It's mutual, somewhere else
鮮やかな わがまま 称えよ
Praise that vivid selfishness
ナイナイばぁで こっち向いて
Peek-a-boo, look over here
滴る未来を 探せよ
Search for the dripping future
次第 愛待って 高まって
Gradually, waiting for love, rising
撃ち放て 狂魔術
Unleash the crazed magic
せーので ここに 集えよ
On the count of three, gather here
闇に 震え けるべろす
Cerberus trembling in the dark
切に 響く 言葉は
Words that resonate deeply
ぶち切れ 破行 パラダイス
Bursting, erratic paradise
キラリ 心の底まで 届け
Sparkling, reach the bottom of the heart
これからも 私の元で
Stay by my side from now on
不思議な力 撃ち放て
Unleash the mysterious power
世界も 笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile
パッパッパッラリラ 歌えば
Pa-pa-pa-rarira, if we sing
一生 一緒 だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
暗い面 ばっか してないで
Don't just keep a dark face
パッパッから さらば 踊れよ
Pa-pa, and then farewell, dance along
視界外線 逸らさないで
Don't look away from your peripheral
今は ただ 離れていかないで
For now, just don't leave me
ヤダヤダ 待って あっち向いて
No, no, wait, look over there
今は まだ 心の準備を
I'm still preparing my heart for now
期待値だって 高まって
Expectations are also rising
パッパッパ 動け 狂魔術
Pa-pa-pa, move, crazed magic
我に ひれ伏せ こよいよ
Prostrate before me tonight
闇を 破れ 召し合えよ
Break the darkness and feast
打つべき者 その名は
The one to be struck, that name is
眠りの 波状 パラダイス
The wave of sleep, paradise
キラリ 心の底まで 届け
Sparkling, reach the bottom of the heart
白黒 つけて あげるから
Because I'll make things clear
不思議な力 ふりかざして
Brandish the mysterious power
みんなで 笑顔になっちゃって
Let's all be filled with smiles
パッパッパッラリラ 歌えば
Pa-pa-pa-rarira, if we sing
一生 一緒 かもね
Maybe we'll be together forever
ヒラリヒラリ と 紫に染まって
Fluttering, fluttering, dyed in purple
これからも あなたの元で
Stay by your side from now on
奇跡の呪文 解き放って
Release the miracle spell
咲かせる 笑顔の花を
Make the flowers of smiles bloom
キラリ 心の底まで 届け
Sparkling, reach the bottom of the heart
これからも 変わらないままで
Stay the same from now on
不思議な力 ほら 宿って
Look, the mysterious power dwells within
世界も 笑顔になっちゃって
Making the whole world smile
パッパッパッラリラ 歌えば
Pa-pa-pa-rarira, if we sing
一生 一緒 だよね
We'll be together forever, right?
絶対 一緒 だよね
We'll absolutely be together forever
あー！
Ahhh!
やったねー！
We did it!
イェーイ！よかったー！
Yay! That was great!
一生、一緒だよねー！
We'll be together forever, right!
かわいかったよー、あくたん。
You were so cute, Akutan.
私たち今日アイドルだね！
We're total idols today!
そうだよ。今日は芸人じゃないんだよ。
Exactly. We're not comedians today.
今日はアイドルだよ！
Today we are idols!
今日はアイドルなんだ。
We really are idols today.
せーの！どーもー！
Ready? Hello there!
見えてるかー？
Can you all see us?
見えてる？
Can you see?
ということで、皆さんどうも！こんあくあ、湊あくあです！そして！
So, hello everyone! Kon-aqua, I'm Minato Aqua! And!
はい、こんばんは、紫咲シオンです！どうも！
Yes, good evening, I'm Murasaki Shion! Hello!
あくシオです！
We're AkuShio!
ということで今日は、あくシオ3Dライブということで！はい！
And so today is the AkuShio 3D Live! Yes!
どうですか？どうですか？お気持ちは？
How is it? How is it? How do you feel?
いいですね！最初「ロキ」から、これ、これね！
It's great! Starting with 'Roki', then this, this right here!
これね！エアギターね！
This! The air guitar!
エアギターね！ジャンジャンジャン、三味線じゃないからねこれ！エアギターだからね！
Air guitar! Strumming away, this isn't a shamisen! It's an air guitar!
アクア...紫色のパレット
Aqua-Murasaki-iro Palette...
いろいろ...ちょっと待って待って、私のオリ曲だよねそれ
Whoa, wait, wait! That's my original song!
アクアは紫色のパレット歌ってメイジ・オブ・バイオレットを...
Aqua sings "Aqua-Murasaki-iro Palette" and "Mage of Violet"...
そしたら「メイジ・オブ・アクアパレット」にならなきゃいけないと思うんだけど
Then it'd have to be "Mage of Aqua Palette," wouldn't it?
あれ？おかしいねこれ
Huh? That's weird.
おかしい！おかしいね
It's weird! It's weird!
ということでね、みんなどうだったかな？ありがとう！
Anyway, how was it, everyone? Thank you!
笑ってる、「草」って言われてる！
They're laughing! They're saying "lol"!
アイドルに向かって「草」って！
Saying "lol" to idols!
そうだよ、今日は私たちアイドルだから！
That's right! We're idols today!
私たち「あくシオちゃん」だからね！
We're "Akushio-chan" after all!
マジで意味わかんないけど、可愛いでしょう？
I don't really get it, but we're cute, right?
あくシオちゃん。今日のサムネ超気に入ってるんだからね
We're Akushio-chan. I really like today's thumbnail!
あくシオちゃんだよ！
It's Akushio-chan!
え、ちょっと待って...え、ちょっと、やだ！
Wait, wait a minute... No!
媚び売らないで！
Don't try so hard to be cute!
私のチャンネルの紫シオン！
On my channel, Murasaki Shion...
媚び売らないで！
Don't try so hard to be cute!
今日はね、最後にね、なんかすごい告知が...
Today, at the very end, there's a big announcement...
あるらしいので、楽しみにしといてくれると嬉しいです！
...apparently, so please look forward to it!
お願いします！
Please do!
じゃあちょっと、もう次の曲、まだまだありますから！
Well then, we still have more songs to go!
まだまだありますから！
Still more to come!
こっからは二人ですかね？
From here on, it's just the two of us?
歌お！
Let's sing!
そうだね、二人で歌おっか！
Right, let's sing together!
あくシオライブ、歌おっか！
Since it's an Akushio live, let's sing!
じゃあその前にちょっとお着替えを...
But before that, we need to change clothes...
あ、そうだそうだ！
Oh, right, right!
ちょっと見ないでよ！
Don't look!
見ないでよ、変態まじで！
Don't look, you perverts! Seriously!
見たいんでしょ、本当は！
You want to see, don't you? Admit it.
あ, シオンの方が壁側にいるから
Oh, Shion is closer to the wall.
しょうがないな
Can't be helped then!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
劣等上等
Bring It On
劣等上等 BRING IT ON
Bring It On, BRING IT ON
野となれ山となれ　マシマシで
Come what may, let's go all out
火に油注いで　そんじゃおさらば
Fanning the flames, then it's goodbye
コミュニケーション気取りで
Pretending to communicate
酒場の見物ばかりじゃつまんねぇ
Just watching from the bar is boring
ほらもっと　間違って上等
Come on, making more mistakes is fine
退屈に手をかけて
Take hold of this boredom
ママ、やっぱ私は
Mom, after all, I...
こんなところじゃ終われない
...can't end up in a place like this
ぬるくて気が触れそう
It's so lukewarm, I'm going crazy
ごっこ遊びも芝居もさよなら
Goodbye to playing house and acting
ずっとこのままなんてさ
Staying like this forever...
いられないよ
...is impossible
ダッダッダ　あたし大人になる
Da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult
酸いも甘いも噛み分けて今
Tasting the sour and the sweet now
パッパッパ　変わる時代
Pa-pa-pa, the changing era
悪いことばかりじゃないでしょう
Isn't just about bad things, right?
過去も、罪も、罰も、すべて
Past, sins, punishment—everything
素手で、愛で、生き抜いてやり返すわ
I'll survive with bare hands and love, and pay it back
Yeah、頂上、あたしたちは Now
Yeah, at the top, we're here now
緑のアイツにボコボコ待ってんね
Waiting to beat up that green guy
さあ、合図になったらもらえる金貨
Now, the gold coins you get when the signal sounds
赤ペン入れてりゃ　どこがダメなんですか
What's wrong with marking it with a red pen?
世間様ちゃっちゃっちゃってコンプリートして
Complacently completing society's expectations
冗談じゃん　落書き
You're joking, it's just a scribble
中指立てたくなるような事ありすぎて
So many things make me want to flip the bird
指が足りねぇから　ハンズアップ　ハンズアップ
Not enough fingers, so hands up, hands up!
もっとだろ？
You want more?
ママ、なんもいらない
Mom, I don't need anything
欲しがります死ぬまでは
I'll be greedy until I die
伸びた背丈　育った街に投げキッス
Blowing a kiss to the city I grew up in
今は届かない　覚悟しとけよ
It won't reach now, just you wait
ダッダッダ　僕ら大人になる
Da-da-da, we're becoming adults
カウンター狙い　痛い日々も
Aiming for a counter, even painful days
タンタンと　かます刺激
Tan-tan, dealing out stimulation
誰も読めない先の展開　それ以上
A future development no one can read, and more
過去も、嘘も、罰も、すべて
Past, lies, punishment—everything
生きて、生き抜いて、覆すわよ
Living, surviving, I'll overturn it all
たったくだらない
Just something so trivial
言葉だけが譲れない
But those words are the only thing I won't give up on
わかるか？　あたしの美学
Do you get it? My aesthetic
この馬鹿正直な
This stupidly honest...
拳一つが
...single fist...
切り札
...is my trump card
ガンガン踊れよ
Dance vigorously
いちぬけた
I'm the first to leave
サラバ！
Farewell!
こんなもんじゃない　だっだっだっ　私大人になる
It's not just this, da-da-da, I'm becoming an adult
つい今雨をも噛み分けて今
Just now, I'm parting the rain and now...
燦々交ざる現代（いま）は僕らを　絶対離さないのだ
The brilliantly mixing present will never let us go
期待待ってくれない　すべてを背負って
Expectations won't wait, carrying everything on my back
生き抜いて上等だわ
Surviving is just fine
それでは皆様お先にバイバイ
Now then, everyone, bye-bye ahead of you
ロマンスの不祥事　逃がさない
I won't let a romance scandal escape
消してあげる
I'll erase it for you
先生！私が大統領になったら、人の男にちょっかいかける女は島流しにします！
Teacher! When I become president, women who mess with other people's men will be exiled!
先生！私が大統領になったら、「いやただの友達だよ～」ってごまかすやつをおへそから電気を流します！
Teacher! When I become president, I'll send electricity through the navels of people who make excuses like "No, we're just friends"!
だだだ大打撃　宣戦布告なのだクローズアップ
Da-da-da major blow, it's a declaration of war, close up
どどど独占欲　揺るぎない敵にサーチライト
Do-do-do possessiveness, searchlights on the unwavering enemy
大嫌いしょうがない　クズは病気ねバイバイバイ
I hate you, it can't be helped. Scum is a sickness, bye-bye-bye
権利・語彙・財産・知名度　何もないけど裁きたい　でしょ？
Rights, vocabulary, wealth, fame... I have none of those, but I want to judge you, right?
だだだ大統領になったらね　まずは君を捕まえるね
When I become president, first I'll capture you
濡れたタオルで洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you confess everything with a wet towel
誰ですかあの子　ダメですかそうですか
Who is that girl? Is she a no-go? I see...
ロマンスの不祥事　逃がさない
I won't let a romance scandal escape
消してあげる　シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
I'll erase it for you, S'il vous pre-pre-president
先生！私が大統領になったら、「ただの仕事の付き合いだよ～」って言うやつは二度と働けなくしてやります！
Teacher! When I become president, I'll make sure people who say "It's just a work relationship" can never work again!
先生！いかにも「いや向こうが強引でさぁ～」っていう男の口にはネジを流し込んで固めてやります！
Teacher! I'll pour screws into the mouths of men who act like "No, she was the aggressive one" and harden them!
みみみ見えちゃう　まるでドロ沼だねアンバランス
I-I-I can see it, it's like a quagmire, unbalanced
ままま丸見え　自作自演なしのスクープね
M-m-m fully visible, a scoop with no staged performance
愛はない理由じゃない　悪くないのねはいはいはい
It's not that there's no love. You're not at fault, yeah yeah yeah
軽薄なママで意気揚々　何もないとかありえない　でしょ？
In high spirits while remaining frivolous. It's impossible for there to be nothing, right?
だだだ大統領になってもね　多分君は変わらないね
Even when I become president, you probably won't change
しらっととぼけて　のらりくらり交わすのね
Playing innocent and avoiding the subject
どうですかこんばんは　本気ですかそうですか
How are you? Good evening. Are you serious? I see...
情熱は不注意　いれますか　消してしまいたい
Passion is carelessness. Shall I put it in? I want to erase it
だだだ大統領になったらね　マジで君を捕まえるね
When I become president, I'll seriously capture you
濡れたタオルで洗いざらい吐かせるね
I'll make you confess everything with a wet towel
どこですか今あんた　見つけちゃったバレちゃった
Where are you now? I found you, you're caught
容赦にはご用心　さようなら　代わりに銃声
Beware of mercy. Goodbye. A gunshot instead
シル・ヴ・プレプレプレジデント
S'il vous pre-pre-president
はー、おかゆ今日もかっこいいなあ
Haa, Okayu is so cool today too.
おかゆ明日結婚しようね
Okayu, let's get married tomorrow.
あーおかゆー！ おかゆー！
Ah, Okayu! Okayu!
は？
Huh?
私のおかゆだけど
She's my Okayu, though.
え？
What?
シオン、おかゆと明日結婚するけどな
Well, I'm getting married to Okayu tomorrow.
え？
What?
待って、おかゆは私と結婚するんだよ
Wait, Okayu is getting married to me.
え、結婚しようって言ってないでしょ
Eh, she didn't say she would, right?
え、でも「待って」って言われてるんだよ
Eh, but she told me to "wait".
違うよ、だっておかゆ明日結婚するって言ってたもん
No, because Okayu said we're getting married tomorrow.
え、それ何回言われてんの？だってもう結婚するって言われて2年近く言われてまだ結婚してないんだよ
Eh, how many times has she told you that? She's been saying that for nearly two years and you're still not married.
そんなことないよ！
That's not true!
ゼクシィ買って、もう結婚してる！
I bought Zexy, we're already married!
あー！もう結婚してる！
Ah! We're already married!
違う！
No!
そうやって約束するだけしといてさ...
You just keep making promises like that...
もう結婚また今度ね、また今度ねって引き延ばしてさ...
And you keep putting off marriage like 'next time, next time'...
違うわよ！
That's not it!
あいつホントに！
She really is...!
そもそもさ、あんた一回も言ったことないくせにさ、
In the first place, you've never even said it once,
おかゆとさ結婚するなんてさ...
but you say you'll marry Okayu...
今待ってくれてんのよ。やっぱり何年も...
She's waiting for me. After all these years...
甘いんだよ、考えが！
You're being naive!
本気よ！
I'm serious!
おかゆとおかゆの愛は...
My love for Okayu is...
負けねえぞ！
I won't lose!
シオンの方が強いから！
Because Shion's is stronger!
私がチューリングラブ歌ってんの！
I'm the one singing Turing Love!
いや、いっぱいコラボしてます！
No, we've collaborated a lot!
私だってコラボしてるし！
I've collaborated with her too!
あっちの方がコラボしてるわよ！
She's collaborated more with me!
（叫び声）
(Shouting)
あいたたたた...
Ouch, ouch, ouch...
痛いなぁ...
That hurts...
あれ？ここどこ？ん？
Wait? Where am I? Huh?
あいたっ！
Ouch!
あれ？あれれ？
Wait? Huh?
私じゃない？
It's not me?
え？ここどこ？私じゃない...
Eh? Where is this? It's not me...
かゆっ。
Itchy.
ちょっ、おケツかゆ。
Wait, my butt's itchy.
え？私？私おケツかかない...あれ？
Eh? Me? I don't scratch my butt... wait?
お腹かゆ。
My stomach is itchy.
もしかして、シオンちゃんこれ？
Could it be that this is Shion-chan?
ちょっと！すみません！
Hey! Excuse me!
おケツかゆ...
My butt's itchy...
私？それは私ですけど...
Me? That is me, but...
え？誰ですか？
Eh? Who are you?
私、誰なんでしょう？
Who am I?
湊あくあです。あなたは誰ですか？
I'm Minato Aqua. Who are you?
あちし...
Atishi...
あちし、メイドの仕事しなきゃ。
Atishi, I have to do my maid work.
違うよね、紫咲シオンさんですよね？あなた。
That's wrong. You're Murasaki Shion-san, right?
え？あなたですよね？紫咲シオンさん。
Eh? You're the one, right? Murasaki Shion-san.
あなた誰ですか？
Who are you?
あちし、あちし、あちし...
Atishi, atishi, atishi...
あちし、誰ですか？
Atishi, who are you?
パーフェクトメイド。
Perfect maid.
お料理もお掃除も大好き。
I love cooking and cleaning.
違うね。違うね。あなたは紫咲シオンさん。私、湊あくあ。
No, that's not right. You're Murasaki Shion-san. I'm Minato Aqua.
もしかして、あなた、湊あくあさんですか？
Could it be, are you Minato Aqua-san?
はい、さっきからそう３回目よ、３回目。
Yes, I've said it three times now.
てことは...てことは、あなたは誰？
That means... that means, who are you?
あちしおん...
Atishion...
あちしおん！
Atishion!
で、このすごい広いぞ。わあ！
And this place is so huge. Wow!
あちしおん。あちしおん、ちょっと気づかなかった。
Atishion. Atishion, I didn't realize for a bit.
あれ？あちし、パーフェクトメイドだからお仕事して...
Wait? Atishi is a perfect maid, so I have to work...
違うよね。違うから仕事はね、しないから。
That's not right. It's different, so you don't do work.
そう。ゲームして。ニート。
Yeah. Just play games. A neet.
あちしニート！
Atishi is a neet!
あちしニート。あちし、メイド、メイド、メイド、メイド。
Atishi is a neet. Atishi is a maid, maid, maid, maid.
アイアムニート！
I am a neet!
違う、ノー、ノー、ノー。メイド、メイド。
No, no, no. Maid, maid.
色々おかしくなっちゃうから、これ。
Everything's going to get messed up if we do this.
入れ替わった！
We swapped!
スパークル
Sparkle
まだこの世界は
Still in this world
僕を飼いならしてたいみたいだ
It seems it wants to keep me tamed
望み通りいいだろう
As you wish, then
美しくもがくよ
I'll struggle beautifully
運命だとか未来とかって
Words like destiny or future
言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと
No matter how much they reach out their hands
届かない場所で僕ら恋をする
We'll fall in love in a place out of reach
時計の針も二人を横目に見ながら進む
The hands of the clock too, advance while looking at us
こんな世界を二人で一生
Through such a world, together for a lifetime
いや何章でも生き抜いていこう
No, through any number of chapters, let's survive
「はじめまして」なんてさ
Words like "nice to meet you"
遥か彼方へと追いやって
Are chased away to far beyond
千年周期を
A thousand-year cycle
一日で息しよう
Let's live through in a single day
辞書にある言葉で
With words found in a dictionary,
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated this ready-made world.
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope,
８月の或る朝
one morning in August.
君は僕の前で
You stood before me,
ハニかんでは澄ましてみせた
bashfully acting cool.
この世界の教科書
With a smile not found
載ってない笑顔で
in any textbook in this world.
嘘みたいな日々を
Days like a lie,
規格外の意味を
meanings beyond measure.
悲劇だっていいから 望んだよ
Even if it's a tragedy, I wished for it.
そしたらドアの外に
Then, outside the door,
君が全部抱えて立っていたよ
you were standing there holding it all.
運命だとか未来だとか
Destiny, the future...
って言葉がどれだけ手を
no matter how far those words
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で
stretch out, they can't reach the place
僕ら 恋をする
where we fall in love.
愛し方さえも
Even in the way I love,
君の匂いがした
I caught your scent.
歩き方さえも
Even in the way I walk,
その笑い声がした
I heard your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなってしまう
One day, everything about you
君のすべてを
will fade away and disappear.
この眼に焼き付けておくことは
To sear it all into my eyes,
もう権利なんかじゃなく
is no longer just a right,
義務だと思うんだ
I believe it's my duty.
運命だとか未来だとか
Destiny, the future...
って言葉がどれだけ手を
no matter how far those words
伸ばそうと届かない 場所で
stretch out, they can't reach the place
僕ら恋をする
where we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock,
横目に見ながら進む
glancing at us as they move forward.
そんな世界を二人で
Through such a world, the two of us,
一生 いや、何章でも
for a lifetime, no, for however many chapters,
生き抜いていこう
let's survive together.
ちょ、何、待って、今すごいいいとこだったのに
Wait, what? It was such a good moment just now!
あくしガニ〜
Akushigani~
あくしガニ！
Akushigani!
あくしガニって何？
What's "Akushigani"?
あくしガニ...
Akushigani...
違うよね？今エモいエモい流れだったでしょ
No, right? We were in a totally emotional flow!
え、あくしガニ？
Eh, Akushigani?
え、ここ海？海？あくしガニ？
Eh, is this the sea? The sea? Akushigani?
あくしガニ〜
Akushigani~
あくしガニ！
Akushigani!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あれ、なんか違うような、あれ？
Wait, something feels off... huh?
ほら、綺麗だな、新宝島...
Look, it's beautiful, like Shin-Takarajima...
綺麗だね。でもなんかちょっと違うような。
It is beautiful. But something's a bit different.
でもあくしガニのほうが綺麗だわ。
But Akushigani is even more beautiful.
えぇ〜？
Ehhh?
ちょっとどういうことさ、何してくれちゃってんのさ、あくしガニって何さ
Wait, what do you mean? What are you doing? What even is "Akushigani"?
なんかそういう流れになっちゃった。
It just turned into that kind of flow.
皆さんどうも、あくしガニ〜
Hello everyone, Akushigani~
新しい挨拶できちゃったよね。
A new greeting was born, wasn't it?
ホロライブ２期生パーフェクトメイドの、あくしガニです。
Hololive 2nd Gen's Perfect Maid, Akushigani.
名前があくしガニさんになってんのよ。
Your name has literally become "Akushigani-san".
おかしいのよ、名前がね、あくしガニさんになってんの。
It's weird! Your name has become Akushigani-san.
あ・く・し・ガ・ニ
A-ku-shi-ga-ni
あくしガニです！
It's Akushigani!
違うよね、ガニさんじゃんそれ。もうガニさんなのよ。
No, that's just "Gani-san". You're already Gani-san.
あくしが苗字。
"Akushi" is the surname.
ガニが名前。
"Gani" is the given name.
新しい人なのよ、それ。
That's a completely new person.
２期生って結構前からいらっしゃるけど、知らないよ、それ。
The 2nd Gen has been around for a while, but I don't know that person.
こんなキャラじゃないの。
You're not this kind of character!
皆さんどうも、こんあくあ〜って感じだよ？
You're supposed to be like, "Hello everyone, Kon-Aqua~", right?
みんなタークアです！
Everyone, I'm Ta-aqua!
皆さんどうも、あくしガニ〜
Hello everyone, Akushigani~
カニカニカニって。お前とカニカニカニって。
"Crab crab crab". Me and you, crab crab crab.
この挨拶、新しい挨拶。
This greeting, the new greeting.
あくしガニ、カニカニカニって。
Akushigani, crab-crab-crab.
使うわ、これから。私が港あくあとして配信するから。
I'll use it from now on. When I stream as Minato Aqua.
違う違う違う！新しい挨拶待って。やだやだやだ。
No, no, no! Wait, the new greeting. No, no, no.
皆さんどうも、あくしガニ、カニカニカニ、カニ！
Hello everyone, Akushigani, crab-crab-crab, crab!
こんあくあ〜！
Kon-Aqua~!
おかしいんだよね、ねえ？
It's weird, isn't it?
おかしいよ、ちょっと。え？
It's a bit weird. Huh?
でも今日から紫咲シオンでしょ？
But from today, you're Murasaki Shion, right?
え、どうしよう私…
Wait, what should I do...
こんばんは、紫咲シオンでちゅ！
Good evening, I'm Murasaki Shion-chu!
ちゅ！ちゅ！ちゅ！
Chuu! Chuu! Chuu!
あ、可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
シオンでちゅ！
I'm Shion-chu!
あてしガニ！あてしガニ！
I'm a crab! I'm a crab!
こっちのほうがだいぶ可愛いんだよね。
This one is much cuter, isn't it?
あてしガニ！あてしガニ！これネタなんよね。
I'm a crab! I'm a crab! This is a gag, you know.
私の体で何やっちゃってんのって感じなんだよね。
It's like, what are you doing with my body?
ガニ股だし。あてしガニ！
And I'm bow-legged. I'm a crab!
違う、違う、違う、違う。ちょっと動いて。
No, no, no, no. Move a little.
ねえ、やば！あてしガニ！
Hey, this is bad! I'm a crab!
ねえ、本当にやばいって！
Hey, this is really bad!
今日からね、ちゅうちゅうね。
From today, it's chuu-chuu.
分かった。ネズミ？
Got it. A mouse?
あ、可愛い。ちょっと可愛すぎるなこれ。
Ah, cute. This is a bit too cute.
あてしカニ！
I'm a crab!
シオンでちゅ！ちゅ！ちゅ！
I'm Shion-chu! Chuu! Chuu!
あてしガニ！あてしガニ！
I'm a crab! I'm a crab!
ねえ、やだ！やだ！
Hey, no! No!
こんなんじゃん！もっと可愛く！あんまり変わらんって。
It's not like this! More cutely! It's not much different.
もっと可愛くして！
Make it more cute!
シオンでちゅ！ちゅ！ちゅ！
I'm Shion-chu! Chuu! Chuu!
さいしゃ、いってらっしゃい！
Saisha, have a good one!
それ違うよ。それダメなやつじゃん。
That's wrong. That's a bad one.
それダメ？それダメ？
Is that bad? Is that bad?
それダメなやつ。それ違うやつ。
That's a bad one. That's the wrong one.
いってらっしゃい！あてしガニっちょ！
Have a good one! I'm a crab-cho!
こんばんばん！シオンにちゅ！
Good evening! A kiss for Shion!
ちょっとさ、そんなことよりさ…
Hey, more importantly than that...
はい、はい、はい。そんなことより。
Yes, yes, yes. More importantly.
ちょっと、あれ、この体どうすんのよ。
Hey, what are we going to do about these bodies?
本当だよ、どうすんのよ。困るよ。
Seriously, what are we going to do. I'm in trouble.
あてしこれから湊あくあとして生きていくしかなくなっちゃうよ。
I'll have no choice but to live as Minato Aqua from now on.
やだよそれ。ずっとあれよ。
I hate that. It'll be like that forever.
何あがるの？やだよ。
What's going up? I hate it.
なんで？戻りたいもん。だってこの体で…
Why? I want to go back. I mean, with this body...
もうやばやばやば。ダメダメダメ。
This is bad, bad, bad. No, no, no.
ガニアイドル。
Crab idol.
ガニアイドルじゃないよ。ガニ好きだけど。
I'm not a crab idol. I like crabs, though.
ガニ界のプリンセス。
Princess of the crab world.
違う、違う、違う。やんよ。やんよ。戻りたいよ。
No, no, no. I hate it. I hate it. I want to go back.
あ、やんなの？普通にゲームしたいの。うん。
Oh, you hate it? I just want to play games normally. Yeah.
どうやったら戻れるの？
How can we go back?
あんた掃除しなさい。
You, go do the cleaning.
ちょっと、あれ、あたし、あたし魔法使いだから掃除しないよ。
Wait, I, I'm a witch so I don't do cleaning.
あんたご飯作りなさい。
You, go make dinner.
なんで？俺なんか立場がちょっと…
Why? My position is a bit...
あんたメイドでしょ？
You're a maid, right?
ちょっとあたしメイドじゃないのよね、今は。
Hey, I'm not a maid right now, you know.
今は違うよ。そうか。
Right now you're not. I see.
うん。でもどうやったら戻れるの？
Yeah. But how can we go back?
教えてあげようか。
Shall I tell you?
教えて。魔法。
Tell me. Magic.
魔法。君なら使えるよ。
Magic. You can use it.
確かに。魔法使いの格好してるけど。
True. I'm dressed like a witch.
無理だよ。わかんない。習ってないもん。
It's impossible. I don't know. I haven't been taught.
え、教えてあげるよ。
Eh, I'll teach you.
急にさ、車の運転してくださいって言われても運転できないじゃん。
Even if you're suddenly told to drive a car, you can't drive it.
はい指出して。はい指出して。
Okay, put your finger out. Put your finger out.
はい指出しました。
Okay, I put my finger out.
行くよ。
Here I go.
しお様ビーム！
Shio-sama Beam!
え？
Eh?
行くよ、じゃあ。
Okay, here goes then.
しお様ビーム！
Shio-sama Beam!
そんなんで戻れるわけないじゃん。
There's no way we can go back with that.
え？なんで？今すごい可愛かったんだけど。
Eh? Why? That was really cute just now.
え、どうすればいいの？え、どうす…え？
Eh, what should I do? Eh, what... eh?
しょうがないな。お手本見せてあげるよ。
Fine then. I'll show you an example.
分かった。
Got it.
紫咲シオンビーム！
Murasaki Shion Beam!
え？これでいいの？
Eh? Is this okay?
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out over that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved into the sand, the sight of you from behind
寄り返す波が 足元をよぎり何かをさらう
The returning waves pass by my feet and sweep something away
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎてゆく
In the evening calm, only the twilight passes by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
I was watching the fireworks that suddenly lit up and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
The summer that surely hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted my ambiguous heart and connected us
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I'll be able to see the same fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do for your smiling face
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動衝
Hurting, being happy, the repeating waves and emotional surges
最終列車の音
The sound of the last train
...言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
...Make it into words and call your name
波打ち際をもう一度
The shoreline once more
もう二度と悲しまずに澄むように
So that we never have to be sad again
ハッと息を飲めば 消えちゃいそうな光だ
If I catch my breath, the light seems like it'll disappear
きっとまだ 胸に住んでいた
I'm sure it was still living in my heart
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future I could touch if I reached out
密かに二人を見ていた
Was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が
The fireworks suddenly...
(パッと花火が)
(...suddenly blossomed)
夜に咲いた
Blossomed in the night
(夜に咲いた)
(...in the night)
夜に咲いて
Blossoming in the night
(夜に咲いて)
(...in the night)
静かに消えた
And quietly disappeared
(静かに消えた)
(...quietly disappeared)
離れないで
Don't leave me
(離れないで)
(...don't leave me)
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer
(もう少しだけ)
(...just a little longer)
もう少しだけこのままで
Just a little longer, like this
あの日見わたした渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out over that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, and the sight of your back
パッと光り咲いた 花火を見ていた
We were watching the fireworks that suddenly lit up and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
I'm sure the summer that hasn't ended yet...
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted our ambiguous hearts and connected them
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to continue
違うんよ、違う！
It's not like that, no!
え？
Huh?
これだと「イエスフォーリンラブ」になるんよ、違うんだよね。
If we do this, it becomes "Yes Fall in Love", that's not it.
違う、でも、うん、やりたいって言って…
No, but, yeah, you said you wanted to do it...
違ったよね！間違えた！
That was wrong! We messed up!
違うんでしょ、間違えたねちょっと。
It was wrong, right? We messed up a bit.
そんなもうさ、ね、いいなんかエモい感じだったのに、なんでそんなことするん、なって。
That was such a, you know, good emotional feeling, why did you do that?
でもやりたいって…
But you said you wanted to...
あーもう！間違えちゃった！
Oh come on! I messed up!
あということでね、えー次が最後の曲になるんですけれども。
Ah, so, the next one will be the last song.
早いね。
That's fast.
早い。なんか時の流れは…
Fast. Somehow the passage of time is...
ね、早いですね。
Yeah, it's fast, isn't it?
ちょっとYouTubeも狂っちゃったけどね。
Even though YouTube went a bit crazy too.
これ何？この手。上げちゃって。
What's this? This hand. You've got it up.
上げちゃってね。上げとこ。下げ下げ…下げとこね。
I've got it up. Let's keep it up. Down down... let's lower it.
ちょっとYouTubeもちょっと狂っちゃったけどね、ま、最後の曲になります。
Well, YouTube went a bit crazy too, but it's the last song.
ということで…
So...
その前に！
Before that!
なに？
What?
すごいあるでしょ、言うことが！
There's something big to say, right!
ん？なに？すごい告知？
Hm? What? A big announcement?
すごい奴よ！言うも！
A big one! Let's say it!
いっちゃう？
Should we?
言わないと。そうだよな。
We have to. That's right.
すごいのは先に言っとかんと。
Gotta say the big thing first.
そうだね。
True.
じゃ、せーのでバンって出るから。
Okay, it'll pop up on 'one, two'.
おっけー。いくよ。いくよ。
Okay. Here we go. Here we go.
せーの！
One, two!
22時！
At 22:00!
動画が！
A video!
上がります！
Will be uploaded!
わーー！出るかな？出るわ。
Waaaa! Will it come out? It will.
メンヘラじゃないもん！
I'm not a Menhera!
ぴえん！
Pien!
ということでね、えーと、このあと22時に、えープレミア公開で、
So, after this at 22:00, as a premiere,
わたくしのあくあちゃんねるのYouTubeで、えーと、
on my Aqua channel YouTube,
「メンヘラじゃないもん！」歌ってみたの動画が上がります！
a "I'm not a Menhera!" cover video will be uploaded!
いぇーい！
Yeeey!
めっちゃ可愛いね、イラスト！
The illustration is super cute!
めっちゃ可愛いのこれ。ちなみにね、MVもめっちゃ可愛いです！
This is super cute. By the way, the MV is also super cute!
見たよ。
I saw it.
知ってるよ。
I know.
そりゃあなた知らなくてどうするのって話でしょ。
Well, of course you'd know. What else would you do?
いや知ってるわ確かに。
Yeah, I know. True enough.
さあ、なので...
Now, then...
よかったらみんなね、この後すぐ！
If you'd like, everyone, right after this!
そう、プレミア公開に私たちもコメントするから。
Yes, we'll be in the comments for the premiere too.
よかったら一緒に見てください！
So please watch it together with us!
見てってねー！
Be sure to watch!
お願いします！
Please do!
めちゃめちゃ可愛いよね、サムネもう可愛い。
It's super cute. Even the thumbnail is cute.
ということで、そしてね...
And with that... also...
ここからがすごい告知！
Here comes a huge announcement!
すごいやつね。
The big one.
一番すごいやつ。絶対見逃しちゃダメなやつ。分かった？みんな。
The biggest one. The one you absolutely can't miss. Got it? Everyone.
みんな分かった？
Did everyone get it?
見るって言ってるよ、見るって。
They're saying they'll watch. They'll watch.
見るって言ってる。私たちもちゃんとコメントしようね。
They're saying they'll watch. Let's make sure we comment too.
可愛いーって。私可愛いーって。
Like, "So cute!" "I'm so cute!"
私の方が可愛い。
I'm the cute one.
私の方が可愛い！
I'm cuter!
私の方が可愛いから！
Because I'm the cuter one!
ほら！私の方が可愛い！
Look! I'm definitely cuter!
えーちょっと、ねえ！媚び売らないで！
Hey, wait! Don't try to win them over!
あくあクルーのみんな... 塩っ子のみんな...
To all the Aqua-crew... To all the Shio-ko...
ちょっと、ねえ、待って！
Hey, wait a minute!
だめ！だめだめだめだめだめ！
No! No, no, no, no, no!
だめなんだから本当にもう。すぐ媚び売ろうとして。
Seriously, stop it. You're always trying to play up to them.
ねえ。もうちゃんとしっかりしてよ本当に。
Hey. Get it together, honestly.
すごい告知の次は？
What's after the huge announcement?
はい、じゃあね。えっと...
Right, well. Um...
まあこれはね、もう告知されているんだけども。
Well, this has already been announced, but...
まあ、あくシオライブということで、もう一回告知しておきましょうか。
Since this is the Akushio Live, let's announce it one more time.
そうですね。せっかくだし。
Good idea. Since we're here.
ということで。え、まあ私たち、なんとですね、二期生、えっと、三周年になりました！
And so. Um, we, the 2nd Gen, have reached our 3rd Anniversary!
そうだよ！みんな三周年だったね！
That's right! We all hit three years!
ということで。そう、そうだから、えっと、三周年の記念グッズが発売になりまして。
And so. Yes, that's why our 3rd Anniversary memorial goods have gone on sale.
じゃあ、私からいきましょう！三つあります全部で。一つ目の告知こちら！
Let's start with mine! There are three in total. Here's the first one!
ババーン！三周年記念グッズがただいま発売中です！イエーイ！
Ta-da! 3rd Anniversary memorial goods are now on sale! Yay!
湊あくあ 活動三周年記念
Minato Aqua 3rd Anniversary Memorial
え、九月の十三日まで発売されております。ということでね。
They'll be available until September 13th. So, check them out.
この中には... あい、ちょっと... ちょっと！ちょっと！ねえ！ちょっと！
Included in this set is... hey, wait... wait! Hey! Stop that!
この中には？
What's in it?
えっと、活動三周年記念の、えっと、フルセット。記念グッズ三種とボイスが一種入っております。
The 3rd Anniversary memorial full set. It includes three types of goods and one set of voices.
三周年を記念した高級感のある、A4の複製原画。イラスト、トモセシュンサク先生が描き下ろしてくれてます。ちょっと邪魔だよ！
An elegant A4 art board to commemorate the 3rd Anniversary. The illustration is by Tomose Shunsaku-sensei. You're in the way!
そして、それ以外にも、Aquacat.Tシャツ。可愛いでしょこれ？ニャニャニャニャ。
And besides that, the Aquacat. T-shirt. Isn't it cute? Meow, meow.
可愛い。
It is cute.
あと、Aquacat.キーホルダーもあります。こちらはカセ先生が描いてくださいました。可愛い！
There's also an Aquacat. keychain. This one was drawn by Kase-sensei. Cute!
可愛いニャン。
Cute, meow.
え、そして、残りシチュエーションボイスもなんと今回は出しております。聞かなくていいです、これは。
And finally, we're even releasing situation voices this time. You don't have to listen to these.
ええ？気になる... 聞くわマジで。危ない。
What? Now I'm curious... I'm definitely listening. That's risky.
はい。ということで告知二つ目はこちら！ちょ邪魔だよ！邪魔だよ！こちら！
Okay. And the second announcement is this! Hey, move! You're in the way! This!
湊あくあ 超BIGぬいぐるみが復刻版として発売されました！イエーイ！
The Minato Aqua Super BIG Plushie is being re-released! Yay!
こちらも期間限定なのでよかったらみんな... みんな買ってね！十三日までです。
This is also for a limited time, so everyone... please get one! It's until the 13th.
シオンたんこれ買ったよね？
Shion-tan, you bought this, right?
これね、まだね、袋に詰まってるよ。開けてない。
That... it's still in the bag. I haven't opened it yet.
開けろよ！開けろよ！開けてカード聞かせてよ！
Open it! Open it! Open it and let me hear the card!
はいということで、そちら概要欄から飛べるのでチェックしてね！ねね！
Alright, you can find the link in the description, so check it out! Okay?
お願いします！そして三つ目はこちら、ダダン！
Please! And the third one is this—ta-da!
ああやっと... やっと言えた... ああやっと...
Ah, finally... I finally get to say it... finally...
新曲「海想列車」のダウンロード＆ストリーミング配信が始まっております！
My new song "Kaisou Ressha" is now available for download and streaming!
こちらね、YouTubeでもMVが投稿されてるのでぜひね、今日は歌わなかったんですけども、ぜひたくさん聴いてくれると嬉しいです。お願いします！じゃあ次シオンちゃんいこうか。
The MV is up on YouTube too. I didn't sing it today, but I'd be so happy if you listened to it a lot. Please do! Okay, Shion-chan, your turn.
はい。
Right.
海想列車〜 そんな曲じゃ... 海想列車〜 ほんの少し...
Sea-Air Train~ That's not how... Sea-Air Train~ Just a little...
違うよね？違うよね？ちょっとエモさなくなっちゃう。
That's wrong, isn't it? That's wrong. You're ruining the mood.
はい、ということでですね。シオンもですね、三周年の記念配信をした時発表したんですが... 三周年記念グッズが発売中です！イエーイドン！
Alright. I also announced this during my 3rd Anniversary stream... my memorial goods are on sale now! Yay, boom!
ジャジャン！こちらタム先生がね、描き下ろしで描いてくれました。ちょっと... まだ映ってないからねそれ。まだ... まだ... ああきた。
Ta-da! These were drawn by Tamu-sensei. Wait... it's not on screen yet. Still... still... ah, there it is.
タム先生のね描き下ろしイラストのブランケットとね、これですね、これ。目覚まし時計。紫咲シオンのボイス入り目覚まし時計。これもタム先生デザインのですね。
A blanket featuring Tamu-sensei's original illustration, and this—this alarm clock. Murasaki Shion's voice alarm clock. Tamu-sensei designed this too.
ボイスが、シオンのボイスがですね、五種類入った収録... 五種類収録したボイス、シオンの声で起きれるっていう素晴らしい目覚まし時計となっております。
It has five different recorded voices of mine. It's a wonderful alarm clock that lets you wake up to my voice.
え、そしてですね、ランダムアクリルキーホルダーが一種。そう、全四種類のうちの一種がですね、記念フルセットでは付いてきます。全部集めたい方はですね、たくさん買ってください。
And there's one random acrylic keychain. One of four types comes with the memorial full set. If you want to collect them all, please buy a bunch.
いかがでしょうか。イエーイ！
How about that? Yay!
あと特典でポストカード...
Also, as a bonus, a postcard...
複製サインメッセージ入りのポストカードが付いてきます。
a postcard with a printed signature and message is included.
はーい！
Okay!
イエーイ！よかったらよろしくお願いします。
Yay! Check it out if you'd like.
概要欄にあるのかな？よろしくね！
Is it in the description? Please check it out!
よろしくねー！
Check it out!
そして次！紫咲シオン、初オリジナル曲
And next! Murasaki Shion's first original song,
「メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット」、ドン！
“Mage of Violet,” boom!
イエーイ！あはは...
Yay! Ahaha...
はい、こちらもですね、3周年の記念配信のあとに出させていただいたんですが...
Yes, this was also released after my 3rd-anniversary stream...
今日もですね、歌いました「メイジ・オブ・ヴァイオレット」。
Today, I sang “Mage of Violet” again.
MVの方が紫咲シオンチャンネルのYouTubeに公開されてるのと...
The MV is published on Murasaki Shion's YouTube channel, and...
あと、スト... ダウンロード＆配信？
Also, str... download & streaming?
ダウンロード＆配信ね。
Download & streaming, right.
ストリーミング...
Streaming...
えー、あの、みたいなのので、そちらもですね...
Ugh, that kind of thing, so please check that out as well...
「海想列車」と一緒に、よろしくお願いします。
Along with “Kaisou Ressha,” thank you.
「海想列車」と一緒に歌ったよね！
We sang it together with “Kaisou Ressha”!
あ、いいじゃん。
Ah, that's good.
いいんじゃなーい？「海想列車」と一緒に歌ったよねってことだ。
Isn't it? Meaning we sang it with “Kaisou Ressha.”
お願いします。ということで、はい、最後の曲に行きましょうかね！
Please. So, yes, let's go to the last song!
行きましょう！そろそろ、あくシオちゃんもね... そう、もうね、そう、あくシオちゃんもね...
Let's go! It's almost time for Akushio-chan... Yes, already, Akushio-chan too...
そろそろね、やっぱもう時間だし、戻らなきゃいけないから、あくシオ星に。
It's about time, we have to go back to the Akushio Planet.
あくシオ星から来たんだ。そうそうそう。
So you came from the Akushio Planet. Yes, yes, yes.
あくシオちゃんもそう、このあとカニ鍋食べて、あくシオ星に帰る。
Akushio-chan too, will eat crab hot pot after this and return to the Akushio Planet.
みんなとお別れの時間、そろそろ...
It's almost time to say goodbye to everyone...
そうだね。寂しいなー。
That's right. It's sad.
シオンちゃんだけハートの目。
Only Shion-chan has heart eyes.
なんでやねん、おかしいやろ！でもハートにしたい。
What?! That's weird! But I want them to be hearts.
ということで、えー、最後の曲はですね...
So, the last song is...
ま、「歌ってみた」でもこちら動画を上げているあの曲を。
Well, that song that we've uploaded a cover video of.
あの有名なね！あれをそうです、歌うんだけれども...
That famous one! Yes, we're going to sing that, but...
やっぱさ、あの人呼んじゃわないとダメだと思うんだよね。
I think we have to call *that* person.
始まらないよね、やっぱりあの人いないと。
It won't start without that person.
あのね、やっぱホロライブの、大きいね、もうこの、何て言うんだろうね、トップ...
You know, that big figure in Hololive, how should I say, the top...
貫録のある、貫録のある笑顔がよく似合う、あのね、こういうやつね、こういうやつ。
That dignified smile suits him well... that person, you know, this kind of guy.
どういう、あ、そういうやつね、こういうやつ。
What kind... oh, that kind of guy, this kind of guy.
これね、これ！みんな、こういうやつ。こういうやつ。小さいのがいれば...
This! Everyone, this kind of guy. This kind of guy. If only there were a small one...
呼ばないとね、呼ばないと、やっぱり。
We have to call him. We have to call him, after all.
ということでね、よかったらコメントで、えー、コールしてくれると嬉しいです。
So, I'd be happy if you could do the call in the comments.
それじゃ、呼ぶよ。みんなせーの！
Then, let's call him. Everyone, one, two...!
YAGOO! (ハイ!) YAGOO! (ハイ!) YAGOO! (ハイ!)
YAGOO! (Hi!) YAGOO! (Hi!) YAGOO! (Hi!)
下から来たー！YAGOOさん！
He came from below! YAGOO-san!
どうもこんにちは。ということで...
Hello there. So...
今回は、えー、YAGOOと一緒に...
This time, with YAGOO...
DJ YAGOOが、DJ YAGOOが...
DJ YAGOO, DJ YAGOO...
バックについて歌っていきたいと思います。
We're going to sing with him in the back.
それじゃ、準備はいい？
Are you ready?
聴いてください。せーの、おこちゃま戦争！
Please listen. One, two, Okochama Sensou!
おこちゃま戦争　作詞：れをる　作曲・編曲：ギガP
Okochama Sensou | Lyrics: Reol | Composition/Arrangement: GigaP
昔々そのまた昔　とある事務所の仲良しな隣人
Once upon a time, long, long ago, in a certain office, there were friendly neighbors
一家共笑
Laughter throughout the house
三歩よりYAGOOが呼ぶ席について
Take three steps and take the seat where YAGOO calls
用意どんでお掃除いたしますな
Ready, set, and I shall clean up
だって僕らはホロ所属　立派な立派な二期生様なんですぞ
Because we're Hololive members, the grand and noble 2nd gen!
ひれ伏せ愚民　君との違いを　バイ・バイスロイ見せてやるぜ
Kneel, you commoners! I'll show you the difference between us, by-by-viceroy!
おい待って待ってまた勝手にそんな　見抜けるよ　あー言えばこー言いう
Hey, wait, wait! Doing that on your own again... I can see through you, whatever you say
はいはいはいはい　あくあ様の仰せのままに
Yes, yes, yes, yes, as Aqua-sama commands
むかつくぜ！まじむかつくぜ！僕に対してなまいきな態度
It's annoying! So annoying! Your cheeky attitude towards me!
閧の声　ゴングを鳴らせ　おうち爆破で宣戦布告
A battle cry! Sound the gong! Declaring war by blowing up the house!
悪戯して　悪ノリして　ほらほら煽ってくスタイルで
Pulling pranks, getting carried away... Look, look, in my taunting style
お仕置きしちゃうぞ　まいどあり　ありがとうで君の負け
I'll punish you! Thanks for your business, you lose!
さあ引き出しと煽り合いの駆け引きで決める　僕の威厳見せるため飴と飴　散る火花両の目
Now, let's decide through a game of strategy and taunts! Show my dignity with sugar and more sugar, sparks fly from both eyes!
僕を私を誰だと思ってる　くらえ！あくあ様がルールブック　間違ってない間違ってない　ちょっと魅力足りないだけ
Who do you think I am? Take that! Aqua-sama is the rulebook. Not wrong, not wrong, just lacking a bit of charm.
さあさあ皆さんお手を拝借　当たり前だろ余裕綽々　生まれながらにしてチート級　きらめく人生がスタート　当然です見てみな由緒　ハイ論破ハイ論破ハイ論破　むかつくぜV・I・C・O・R・Y
Come on, everyone, give us a hand! Of course, I'm cool as a cucumber. A cheat-level life from birth, a sparkling life begins. Naturally, look at my pedigree. Yes, refuted! Yes, refuted! Yes, refuted! Annoying, V-I-C-O-R-Y!
はいはいはいはい　はなまるよくできました
Yes, yes, yes, yes, you did a great job!
おこちゃま戦争
Childish War
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously, I'm so annoyed!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Spouting such cheekiness at me,
とっておきをきみに見舞え
I'll give you a taste of my best move.
報復制裁！　挑発しちゃって
Retaliatory punishment! I'll provoke you,
意地悪して　一枚上
be mean to you, and stay one step ahead.
チャンスは貰ってくぜ　スタンスで
I'll be taking every chance with my stance.
痛恨ミス！　あっちゃっちゃー
A critical mistake! Oh, snap!
お生憎様だね　きみの負け！　イェーイ！
Tough luck, it's your loss! Yay!
だけどきみ　きみだけが
But you, only you,
僕に似合いのライバル
are the rival that suits me.
私に似合いのライバル
The rival that suits me.
落ちるのも　凹むのも
Falling down or getting depressed,
調子狂わされるから
because you throw me off my game,
今宵もあんたと　やーいやーいやーい！
I'll be with you again tonight, nya-nya-nya!
大体いつも上から目線で　暴走するから
You're always so condescending and running wild,
私が後ろから　ブレーキかけなきゃいけないし
so I have to be the one to step on the brakes.
上の空になってるあんた　見てんのもしんどいし
It's exhausting watching you being all spaced out,
いい加減にしろよ　このお節介なだけの　ニセ看板
knock it off, you meddlesome fake figurehead.
後輩達もお困りですよ　クソガキすぎて
Even the juniors are troubled because you're such a brat.
あぁ？もう　うっせーわ
Huh? Shut up already!
けじめをつけましょ！
Let's settle this!
白黒はっきり！
Clear as black and white!
あー　もう　うるせー！
Ah, geez, you're annoying!
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously, I'm so annoyed!
憎まれ口はお口をチャック
Zipper those hateful words,
鬨の声　ゴングを鳴らせ
shout the battle cry, ring the gong.
ひれ伏せ！　エンペラーはこの私
Kneel! The emperor is me!
悪戯して　悪乗りして
Playing pranks, getting carried away,
ほらほら煽ってくスタイルで
look, look, I'm riling you up with my style.
魔入ったか？　いただきまーす
Had enough? Thanks for the meal!
毎度ありがとうで　きみの負け！
Thanks as always, it's your loss!
まさかの　引き分け！？
What, a draw!?
Illust すみちり / Inst ギガ/Reol
Illust: Sumichiri / Inst: Giga/Reol
Movie 萌織/こーせー.h / Dance あゆん
Movie: Moori/Kose-h / Dance: Ayun
Special Thanks けだま / Background art by あくシオ
Special Thanks: Kedama / Background art: Aku-Shio
初 3D Live
かわいい あくシオちゃん
First 3D Live
Cute Aku-Shio-chan